<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
cached data at 23:43:56
cached id 76aaeee55f1a2cd366a5162c3f82fb79
-->
<rss version="2.0" 
		xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
		xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
		xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"><channel><atom:link href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/feeds/rss/incidents/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><title>InciWeb National Incidents</title><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov</link><description>Latest incident updates nationally</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 23:43:57 -05:00</pubDate><language>en-us</language><item><title>Silver Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 22:49:28 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 22:49:28 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>40.223333333333 -106.655</georss:point><geo:lat>40.223333333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-106.655</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5985/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5985/</guid><description>Thursday noon, September 13, 2018What’s New: As of noon on Thursday, the fire has grown to 6,870 acres. Additional growth is occurring to the N/NE.A pre-evacuation notice has just been issued by Grand County for residents in the Lake Agnes, Rabbit Ears Village and Bear Mountain Ranch areas NE of the fire. http://GCemergency.com for more info. Pre-evacuation notice was also issued for Gore Lakes, Latigo Ranch, and Old Park.There is a hot spot on the SE portion of the fire near Latigo Ranch, which is a priority for suppression.The fire has moved past the National Forest/State boundary and is established on Milk Creek State Trust land.An updated area closure is still in progress and is anticipated to be in place today.Efforts are still underway to evacuate hunters in GMU 27 who are south of the Green Creek fire scar. A Type II Incident management Team has been ordered.Thursday a.m., September 13, 2018What’s New: No structures are immediately threatened. The nearest homes are along...</description></item><item><title>Boot Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 22:47:59 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 22:47:59 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>38.395555555556 -119.45138888889</georss:point><geo:lat>38.395555555556</geo:lat><geo:long>-119.45138888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6190/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6190/</guid><description> Two days of sustained high winds maxing over 40 miles per hour has not adversely impacted the Boot Fire. Firefighters are calling it 95% contained today. The remaining uncontained fire area is in the northwestern section above Bootleg Canyon, where it is stubbornly holding a small bit of heat.  Firefighters have been ensuring high winds do not blow any embers outside containment lines. They are also backhauling supplies and removing flagging, garbage and other debris generated from suppression activities. This activity will continue through Friday. A transfer of command back to the Humboldt-Toiyabe National Forrest will occur Saturday morning.  As firefighters work to complete the remaining containment lines, other firefighters are working on suppression repair activities. Suppression repair is an important final step of managing wildland areas affected by wildfires. Over the next few days, firefighters will install waterbars, pull back berms and scatter vegetation back across...</description></item><item><title>Paola Ridge Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:50:14 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:50:14 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.310555555556 -113.65138888889</georss:point><geo:lat>48.310555555556</geo:lat><geo:long>-113.65138888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6140/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6140/</guid><description>FIRE SUMMARY: The Paola Ridge Fire is burning in the Flathead National Forest. This fire is being managed with modified confine and contain strategy with indirect tactics; fire fighter and public safety is a priority. The fire is burning in steep terrain with subalpine forest and brushy avalanche chutes.  GENERAL INFORMATION:The Flathead National Forest and our interagency partners experienced lighting storms throughout the northwest Montana zone on the evening of August 11th. Multiple fires were reported, initial attack is occurring, resources are responding, and more firefighting resources are being ordered. There are no evacuations at this time for this incident, however and EVACUATION WARNING is in place for a small number of residences near Essex. Please follow @FlatheadOES, as warning notices or evacuations will be coordinated through this partner.  Video of the September 4th community meeting is available at https://youtu.be/Vcn-br-QV9A  A story map of the progression of the...</description></item><item><title>Gold Hill Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:50:04 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:50:04 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.576666666667 -115.52638888889</georss:point><geo:lat>48.576666666667</geo:lat><geo:long>-115.52638888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6143/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6143/</guid><description>Highway 68 (Pipe Creek Road/South Fork Yaak Road) is open to vehicular traffic. Please observe the posted 25 miles per hour speed limit between Mile Marker 15 and Mile Marker 17. There may still be delays and intermittent closures due to fire activity, so please plan accordingly.</description></item><item><title>Kerlin Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:48:04 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:48:04 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>40.6275 -123.5075</georss:point><geo:lat>40.6275</geo:lat><geo:long>-123.5075</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6189/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6189/</guid></item><item><title>Klondike Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:39:16 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:39:16 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>42.369444444444 -123.86027777778</georss:point><geo:lat>42.369444444444</geo:lat><geo:long>-123.86027777778</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5998/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5998/</guid><description>September 13    Current daily fire update and information map for Klondike and Taylor Creek Fires. Daily briefing videos posted here for Klondike West Zone. Click here for video on fire behavior and the use of retardants and gels.    Road Closures Bear Camp Road, from the intersection with the Merlin-Galice Road (Josephine County Road #2400 and #2401) west to the intersection with Forest Service Road 33, will remain open for the Agness and Galice residents, permit holders, and lodges until further notice. The Weather forecast indicates this will remain in effect for several days; however, unexpected fire behavior could cause a complete closing to all non-fire traffic at any time. We really appreciate the public’s patience and cooperation. If there is unexpected fire behavior or conditions change allowing tactical firing to begin, the road will be closed to all non-fire traffic until it is safe for the public. Road 3313 in the Rogue River Siskiyou National Forest is also closed from...</description></item><item><title>Delta Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:03:08 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:03:08 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>40.923333333333 -122.40833333333</georss:point><geo:lat>40.923333333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-122.40833333333</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6191/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6191/</guid><description>September 13, 2018: Morning Update | Map | Morning Video | Smoke OutlookNew Announcement: Interstate 5 Open in Both Directions (9/18 6 p.m.)Current Situation (as of 9/13, 6 p.m.): 59,915 Acres24% Contained3,264 Personnel17 Structures Destroyed9/13 Evening Summary:Today, firefighters had success in constructing fireline directly along the fire's perimeter along the northern, western, and southern edges of the fire. Aircraft assisted with fire activity on the west side of Interstate 5. The fire passed through unburned fuels within containment lines on the northeastern area of the fire between Gibson and Sims Roads. Interstate 5 closed temporarily and re-opened to traffic in both directions around 6 p.m. Community Meeting: A recording of the September 13 community meeting in Dunsmuir will be available the following morning or earlier. Closures, Evacuations, and Shelters: view the daily update    </description></item><item><title>Boundary Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:59:38 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:59:38 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.979722222222 -113.97611111111</georss:point><geo:lat>48.979722222222</geo:lat><geo:long>-113.97611111111</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6170/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6170/</guid><description>   The Boundary Fire was reported August 23 at approximately 6:15 pm. The fire is located in the Boundary Creek Valley, near the Campbell Mountain area west of Upper Waterton Lake in northeast Glacier National Park.  All trails originating from Goat Haunt are closed. Video of the September 4th community meeting is available at https://youtu.be/Vcn-br-QV9AA story map of the progression of the fire is available at http://nifc.maps.arcgis.com/apps/MapSeries/index.html?appid=25498813ba044f548c2315e9eb6d2d22 For detailed trail closure information in Glacier National Park, visit https://www.nps.gov/glac/planyourvisit/conditions.htm.For information regarding area closures and information pertaining to Waterton Lakes National Park in Alberta, Canada visit https://www.pc.gc.ca/en/pn-np/ab/waterton/securite-safety/pnlw-wlnp-feu-fire-2018.  </description></item><item><title>Howe Ridge Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:46:52 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:46:52 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.642777777778 -113.91638888889</georss:point><geo:lat>48.642777777778</geo:lat><geo:long>-113.91638888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6135/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6135/</guid><description>On the evening of August 11, lightning ignited a fire on Howe Ridge, northwest of Lake McDonald in Glacier National Park. On Sunday, August 12, windy and dry conditions fueled the fire to rapidly expand. Evacuation orders were issued for the North Lake McDonald road, Lake McDonald Lodge area, Sprague Creek and Avalanche Campgrounds and the Going-to-the-Sun road from the foot of Lake McDonald to Logan Pass (32 miles). On Sunday, August 19, an additional evacuation order was issued for the Fish Creek Campground.  Areas of the fire are visible from some park webcams, depending on weather conditions and fire behavior. Webcams can be found here: https://www.nps.gov/glac/learn/photosmultimedia/webcams.htm he majority of Glacier National Park is open and not affected by the fire. Open areas include Apgar, Two Medicine, St. Mary, Many Glacier and the North Fork.   Video of the September 4th community meeting is available at https://youtu.be/Vcn-br-QV9AA story map of the progression of the...</description></item><item><title>Coal Ridge Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:37:42 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:37:42 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.723333333333 -114.50166666667</georss:point><geo:lat>48.723333333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-114.50166666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6142/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6142/</guid><description> After 9/6/18, Coal Ridge Fire updates will be published on InciWeb on Thursdays unless significant activity occurs. The Coal Ridge Fire is burning in the Flathead National Forest 10 miles west of Polebridge, Montana. This fire is being managed with modified confine and contain tactics, with fire fighter and public safety as a priority. The fire is burning in steep terrain with subalpine forest and brushy avalanche chutes. There are no evacuation warnings in place on this incident. Any warning notices or evacuations will be coordinated with the Flathead Office of Emergency Services.Following lightning storms across the Flathead National Forest evening of August 11, the Coal Ridge Fire was detected the next morning. A Type 1 Fire Management Team is assigned to the fire. Video of the September 4th community meeting is available at https://youtu.be/Vcn-br-QV9A  A story map of the progression of the fire is available at...</description></item><item><title>Whale Butte Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:36:31 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:36:31 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.854722222222 -114.47388888889</georss:point><geo:lat>48.854722222222</geo:lat><geo:long>-114.47388888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6149/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6149/</guid><description> The Whale Butte Fire is burning in the Flathead National Forest 10 miles northwest of Polebridge, Montana. This fire is being managed with modified confine and contain tactics, with fire fighter and public safety as a priority. The fire is burning in steep terrain with subalpine forest and brushy avalanche chutes. Following lightning storms across the Flathead National Forest evening of August 11, the Whale Butte Fire was detected the next morning. A Type 1 Fire Management Team is assigned to the fire. Video of the September 4th community meeting is available at https://youtu.be/Vcn-br-QV9A  A story map of the progression of the fire is available at http://nifc.maps.arcgis.com/apps/MapSeries/index.html?appid=25498813ba044f548c2315e9eb6d2d22 </description></item><item><title>Cat Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:06:50 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:06:50 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>36.365 -112.02861111111</georss:point><geo:lat>36.365</geo:lat><geo:long>-112.02861111111</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6109/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6109/</guid><description>The Cat Fire is at 0% containment and is in monitor status. Containment figures are calculated based on a fire's interaction with constructed or natural fireline. Since the Cat Fire never burned up to the constructed or natural firelines, no official containment was reached; however, there is little fire activity on the fire perimeter with only a few interior hot spots still burning. The fire remains within the initial planning area set by fire managers. The fire area remains closed as outlined in closure order 07-18-10F# Closure Order 07-18-10F#. Smoke update: Both the Cat Fire &amp; Stina Fire are exhibiting minimal activity; however, we are experiencing an increase in regional haze throughout many communities in Northern Arizona. Today’s satellite imagery indicates this haze is attributable to multiple wildfires across the west to include Southern Oregon.</description></item><item><title>Sterling Complex (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:06:48 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:06:48 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.618888888889 -115.10388888889</georss:point><geo:lat>48.618888888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-115.10388888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6137/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6137/</guid><description> The Rexford/Fortine District assumed command of the fire. The fire is being managed by a local type 4 organization. Fire personnel will continue to patrol the perimeter, mop-up interior smokes, followed by rehab work. Temperatures are expected be below normal with a chance of precipitation. The closure order is still in effect for public and fire fighter</description></item><item><title>Seaman Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:06:30 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:06:30 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>40.706388888889 -105.25111111111</georss:point><geo:lat>40.706388888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-105.25111111111</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6201/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6201/</guid><description> The Seaman Fire is located approximately 12 miles northwest of Fort Collins, Colo. and half-mile north of Colorado Highway 14 at Smith Bridge. The fire was started by a lightning strike on Tuesday September 11 west of Seaman Reservoir. The fire is burning on steep terrain in mixed grass/brush and pockets of conifers in the area of the previous 2012 Hewlett burn scar. Eleven structures plus outbuildings are threatened in the Smith Bridge area. A voluntary evacuation of the Smith Bridge area is in place. There are currently no road closures. UPDATE- September 13, 2018 7:00 p.m.  Firefighters on the #SeamanFire continued to make good progress today. The fire, located in the lower Poudre Canyon, is currently at 35 percent containment and about 231 acres in size. Very light smoke from the fire was visible from Fort Collins, as the fire continues to burn in the grasses and pockets of ponderosa pine entirely within the 2012 Hewlett Fire burn scar.     There is a closure order in effect for...</description></item><item><title>Davis Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:03:28 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:03:28 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.957777777778 -115.93305555556</georss:point><geo:lat>48.957777777778</geo:lat><geo:long>-115.93305555556</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6074/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6074/</guid><description>The Three Rivers District has assumed command of the Davis Fire. Resources continue slash removal and fire suppression rehabilitation. Fire behavior is minimal with creeping and smoldering, no new growth. Updates will take place weekly or if there is significant fire growth or changes in the closure order. Temperatures are expected to be below normal with a chance of precipitation. The best chance for precipitation is Sunday..</description></item><item><title>Pole Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:56:12 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:56:12 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>39.805833333333 -111.66055555556</georss:point><geo:lat>39.805833333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-111.66055555556</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6199/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6199/</guid><description>The Pole Creek Fire is actively burning in rough terrain and is being driven by high winds. Rapid fire growth has occurred with extreme fire behavior yesterday and today due to very dry, warm, and windy weather conditions. Evacuations and Forest closures are in effect. A Type 1 Team will in-brief tonight and assume command of the fire Friday morning. The fire is currently 2% contained and estimated to be around 20,000 acres. 208 personnel are</description></item><item><title>Horse Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:42:16 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:42:16 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>37.304444444444 -107.29972222222</georss:point><geo:lat>37.304444444444</geo:lat><geo:long>-107.29972222222</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6181/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6181/</guid><description>The Horse Fire is located 16 miles northwest of Pagosa Springs, Colorado and 8 miles north of highway 160. The fire was started by a lightning strike that was discovered on Tuesday August 28. The fire is burning on steep rugged terrain in dense mixed conifers with pockets of aspen and oak brush. No structures are threatened, and nearby powerline infrastructure is being considered in the incident objectives.  Fire managers are using a combination of direct and indirect tactics on this low intensity fire. Cloud cover and intermittent showers over the course of two days have slowed fire growth. San Juan National Forest has implemented a special order closing an area, roads, and trails to public entry in the vicinity of the fire. The West Monument Road (NFSR 630), Devils Mountain Trail (NFST 600) and the Horse Creek Trail (NFST 689) are some of the more well-known routes affected by the closure. Please check the San Juan National Forest website for current closures and update changes....</description></item><item><title>Goshute Cave Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:42:08 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:42:08 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>40.062777777778 -114.84583333333</georss:point><geo:lat>40.062777777778</geo:lat><geo:long>-114.84583333333</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6165/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6165/</guid><description>The lightning-ignited Goshute Cave Fire in the Goshute Canyon Wilderness, about 55 miles north of Ely, Nev., continues to show internal activity with occasional torching of unburned fuels.There has been no perimeter growth except for the southern flank where growth is minimal. Firefighter and public safety is the top priority. Roads and trails within the fire area remain closed for firefighter and public safety.The BLM Ely District Sunday evening assumed management of the 31,239-acre fire from Bob Fry’s Northern Rockies Incident Management Team. Currently on scene is a Type 4 incident commander, five engines, two water tenders and a Type 3 helicopter to patrol and monitor the fire area.White Pine County residents, recreationalists and motorists on U.S. Highway 93 can expect to see occasional smoke from the fire that was first reported at about 3 p.m., Monday, Aug.</description></item><item><title>Mendocino Complex (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:39:44 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:39:44 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>39.24 -123.11</georss:point><geo:lat>39.24</geo:lat><geo:long>-123.11</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6073/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6073/</guid><description>The Mendocino Complex is comprised of two fires, the River Fire and the Ranch Fire. These two fires are being managed by the U.S. Forest Service. The River Fire is located northeast of the community of Hopland, and the Ranch Fire is located northeast of Ukiah, in Lake County and Mendocino County, California. The Ranch Fire in the Mendocino National Forest north of Clearlake is currently in suppression repair. The expected containment date has been adjusted to September 9, 2018. Type 2 Incident Management Team, Southern California Interagency Management Team 3 (Wakoski), assumed command of the Mendocino Complex at 0700 on 9/4/2018. Forest officials have issued a new Forest Order for the Ranch Fire that reduces the size of the closed area due to fire activity on the Mendocino National Forest. Forest Order No. 08-18-15 goes into effect Sunday, Sept. 2, 2018. The area is closed due to fire suppression and rehabilitation activities that create a hazard to the public, including the use of...</description></item><item><title>Riggs Fire &amp;amp; Lonely Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:21:55 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:21:55 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>37.466388888889 -112.21277777778</georss:point><geo:lat>37.466388888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-112.21277777778</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6202/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6202/</guid><description>The Riggs fire and the Lonely Fire continue to grow in size on lands administered by the Dixie National Forest, Bryce Canyon National Park, and Kanab Field Office BLM. The Lonely Fire is about 1.5 miles north of the Riggs fire. The Lonely fire was also started by lightning, and is managed under the same incident command as the Riggs fire. Decisions to manage or suppress fires are dependent on numerous factors including risk to firefighting resources, public safety, weather, fire behavior, availability of additional support, risk to valuable resources and private property. The area that the Riggs Fire and Lonely Fire are burning has not been impacted by fire for many years resulting in an unnatural buildup of forest fuels. These fires will help to reduce these fuels and return the area to a more natural condition and in turn decrease the risks from unwanted fires. The option to allow some naturally ignited wildland fires to provide benefits to the resource instead of suppressing them...</description></item><item><title>Fork  (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:20:46 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:20:46 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>34.240555555556 -117.85194444444</georss:point><geo:lat>34.240555555556</geo:lat><geo:long>-117.85194444444</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6196/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6196/</guid><description>The Fork Fire was reported at 11:58 am September 9, 2018 on Highway 39 near the junction of East Fork Road. The Fire is currently 166 acres 98% contained.State Route - Highway 39 is closed, two miles north of Sierra Madre Blvd, in the City of Azusa. The East Fork area is open. Burro Canyon Shooting Park, Camp Williams, Oaks picnic area and the East Fork trail head can be accessed by taking the Glendora Mountain Road. The West and North Fork recreation areas along with Coldbrook and Crystal Lake Campgrounds remain closed. The San Gabriel Canyon Off Highway Vehicle (OHV) area will be closed this weekend September 15 &amp; 16. The OHV area will be used as a staging area by Southern California Edison, who will be repairing and replacing power poles and lines above HWY 39, that were affected by the fire.Crews continue to improve containment lines, patrol the fire area and</description></item><item><title>Noland Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:06:12 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 19:06:12 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>33.683888888889 -109.04138888889</georss:point><geo:lat>33.683888888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-109.04138888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6204/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6204/</guid><description>The Noland Fire, currently at 100 acres was discovered on September 7 and is located west of Saddle Mountain on the Gila National Forest. The fire is burning on the ground and consuming heavy fuels. There are two type 6 engines, one hot shot crew, and two small handcrew modules on the fire monitoring and assessing and protecting values at risk.</description></item><item><title>Miriam Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 18:31:36 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 18:31:36 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>46.609722222222 -121.34972222222</georss:point><geo:lat>46.609722222222</geo:lat><geo:long>-121.34972222222</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6066/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6066/</guid><description>The area closure for the Miriam and Clear Fork Fires has been reduced in size on September 7, 2018.The Miriam Fire was detected on July 30 at approximately 10:00 a.m. after lightning passed through the area on July 28. The fire is burning within the Goat Rocks Wilderness on the Naches Ranger District of the Okanogan-Wenatchee National Forest 32 miles southwest of Naches, Washington. The fire is east of the White Pass Ski Area, south of Highway 12, and west of the Tieton River. The Clear Fork Fire is burning in the Goat Rocks Wilderness on the Gifford Pinchot National Forest. The fire is located southwest of Shoe Lake and approximately 2 miles west of the Miriam Fire. This fire was detected on August 8, likely the result of lightning in the area on August 4.These fires are being managed with a combined contain, confine, and monitor strategy in order to protect public and firefighter safety; the White Pass Ski Resort and surrounding area; recreational cabins, camps and resorts on Clear...</description></item><item><title>Surprise Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 17:47:46 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 17:47:46 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>47.924444444444 -116.32527777778</georss:point><geo:lat>47.924444444444</geo:lat><geo:long>-116.32527777778</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6125/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6125/</guid><description>The Surprise Creek Fire, located south of Faset Peak in the Independence Creek drainage, started on July 27, 2018. Fire activity was increased during high temperatures and winds on August 10th. The Idaho Panhandle National Forests assumed command of this incident on Wednesday, September 5 at 6 am as a Type 4 Incident.</description></item><item><title>Miles Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 17:16:40 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 17:16:40 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>42.825833333333 -122.80666666667</georss:point><geo:lat>42.825833333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-122.80666666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5966/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5966/</guid><description>Firefighters continue to patrol and secure the fire’s perimeter as well as repair lines to a more natural. Crews are being reallocated to other areas of the fire as work is completed. Personnel are locating and evaluating equipment no longer in use for suppression or repair work and will release it to other incidents if needed.The Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) team that arrived earlier this week continues to assess the area and will make recommendations on how best to mitigate unstable landscapes in order to prevent the loss of critical resources. BAER teams are staffed by specially trained professionals such as hydrologists, soil scientists, engineers, biologists, vegetation specialists, archeologists, and others who rapidly evaluate the burned area and prescribe emergency stabilization treatments.Appropriate hazard reduction for employees, contractors, and the public may be needed. This work includes the identification and mitigation of danger trees next to roads, trails,...</description></item><item><title>Columbine District Prescribed Burns (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 17:10:08 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 17:10:08 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>37.238888888889 -107.53472222222</georss:point><geo:lat>37.238888888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-107.53472222222</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6193/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6193/</guid><description>PRESCRIBED BURNING CONTINUES ON THE COLUMBINE RANGER DISTRICT -OPERATIONS HAVE NOW BEGUN IN THE YELLOW JACKET AREA ________________________________________________________________________________________   Prescribed burning resumed on the Columbine Ranger District in the Yellow jacket area today. This area is located south of US 160 in the Lange Canyon area. Burning operations may continue in this area for several days.1,800 total acres in the lower Sauls Creek Area were successfully burned over the past three days. Aerial operations occurred on Monday September 10, to help fill in the un-burned areas in those units. No additional ignitions will occur today, Tuesday the 11th. Fire personnel will be monitoring the lower Sauls Creek burn area.  Please note there were three lightning strikes in the vicinity Sunday, fortunately there were plenty of fire personnel nearby to respond.  The San Juan National Forest is conducting these prescribed burns on the Columbine Ranger District,...</description></item><item><title>Bacon Rind Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 16:44:43 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 16:44:43 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>44.967777777778 -111.10222222222</georss:point><geo:lat>44.967777777778</geo:lat><geo:long>-111.10222222222</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5992/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5992/</guid><description>On September 12th the Bacon Rind Fire received .12 inches of rain and a dusting of snow.The Bacon Rind Fire was detected Friday, July 20th around 8:00 p.m. It is burning within the Monument Unit of the Lee Metcalf Wilderness in the Custer Gallatin National Forest and within Yellowstone National Park. A type 3 Incident Management Team is managing the fire in cooperation with the Custer Gallatin National Forest and Yellowstone National Park. The fire can be seen from Highway 191. Smoke may be visible from Highway 191 and the speed limit has been reduced to 45 MPH. Please be cautious when driving along the road and only stop in designated pullouts. There could be times that smoke will reduce visibility along the road, so please use caution.  Wildland fire is an essential, natural process that is crucial to the long-term health of the Greater Yellowstone Ecosystem. Many plants and animals are dependent on fire for their survival. The Bacon Rind Fire is burning in an area that has not seen...</description></item><item><title>Monument Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 16:38:06 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 16:38:06 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>44.968333333333 -111.85111111111</georss:point><geo:lat>44.968333333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-111.85111111111</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6122/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6122/</guid><description>         Current Numbers:      Monument fire: 6,614 acres, 56% contained.     Wigwam fire: 4,087 acres, 100% contained.       Assigned resources: Fire Engine 1; Total Fire personnel: 5           A Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) team has completed their assessment of the burn severity of these fires and fire officials are preparing to work on the recommendations regarding erosion control, road maintenance and removal of hazard trees. Local crews continue to monitor and patrol the fire areas and take action on where conditions are safe. Smoke from interior burning will continue to show on the fires until they receive significant rain and snow.         Road closures have been lifted, however, people traveling in the fire area need to use caution as there are fire personnel working in these areas and there is still active fire and many fire weakened trees within the interior.         Archery hunting season has opened and it is recommended hunters carry a saw with them as they...</description></item><item><title>Terwilliger Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 16:15:23 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 16:15:23 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>44.083611111111 -122.23777777778</georss:point><geo:lat>44.083611111111</geo:lat><geo:long>-122.23777777778</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6160/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6160/</guid><description>The Terwilliger Fire was reported on August 19, 2018, around 3:21pm located approximately approximately five miles southeast of Blue River, Oregon.  Oregon Department of Forestry, US Forest Service fire crews and local landowners responded to suppress the fast moving fire.  Following extended initial attack efforts, additional personnel and equipment were ordered. An incident management team was requested to help manage the growing fire.  The fire surrounds the Cougar Reservoir and numerous recreation sites and prompted the Willamette National Forest to implement the Terwilliger Area Closure for public safety. The Terwilliger Fire remains within the boundaries of the McKenzie Ranger District, Willamette National Forest, including the Three Sisters Wilderness.  The fire is being managed as a full suppression fire.</description></item><item><title>Platypus Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 15:38:11 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 15:38:11 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>34.943055555556 -111.87</georss:point><geo:lat>34.943055555556</geo:lat><geo:long>-111.87</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6061/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6061/</guid><description> The Platypus Fire is a lightning caused fire discovered July 28, 2018. Location: Approximately 4 miles northwest of Sedona in Red Rock Secret Mountain Wilderness more than 6 miles from the nearest trailhead. (Lat/Long: 34.94291, -111.8701) Current size:1,250 acres.  Resources: Coconino NF Fuels Crew 4, lookouts and aircraft periodically monitor the fire as it’s needed because of the inaccessible to firefighters over the steep and rocky terrain. Predicted smoke impacts: Smoke is visible from Sedona and the Verde Valley. Current closures: Secret Mountain Trail Recent and current operations: This fire is being back burned by Fuels Crew 4 in the Red Rock Secret Mountain Wilderness. Firefighter working in the area are working from a spike camp on the mountain.</description></item><item><title>Hurricane Florence - Raleigh RSOI (Hurricane)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 14:37:07 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 14:37:07 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>35.720833333333 -78.6575</georss:point><geo:lat>35.720833333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-78.6575</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6200/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6200/</guid><description>In response to Hurricane Florence's pending impacts to North Carolina, the N.C. Emergency Management, N.C. National Guard and the N.C. Forest Service established a Raleigh-based Receiving Staging Onward Integration (RSOI) operation. Personnel will be supporting and tracking response operations for approximately 1,000 responders, who are expected to begin arriving Tuesday, September 11.    Resources from across the nation will be checked in and logistically supplied and deployed throughout the state where needed.</description></item><item><title>Cougar Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 14:34:11 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 14:34:11 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.266111111111 -116.17222222222</georss:point><geo:lat>48.266111111111</geo:lat><geo:long>-116.17222222222</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6081/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6081/</guid><description> This site will be updated weekly on Friday. Next update will be posted on September 21.Cougar Fire is located south of Jost Creek and north of Porcupine Lake, approximately 5 miles east of Hope, Idaho. The fire was started on July 27, 2018 by lightning. The fire is currently in patrol and monitor status. Smoke will continue to be visible from isolated hot spots. Command of the fire transferred to a Type 3 team on Tuesday, September 11 at 6 a.m. </description></item><item><title>Wapiti Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 14:04:21 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 14:04:21 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>44.164166666667 -115.19388888889</georss:point><geo:lat>44.164166666667</geo:lat><geo:long>-115.19388888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6176/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6176/</guid><description>9-13-2018 a.m. Wapiti Fire UpdateFire Information - Contact Lowman Ranger District208-259-3361  Fire transitioned to local resources management; area closures remain in place  STAGE 1 RESTRICTIONS FOR BOISE NATIONAL FOREST REMAIN IN EFFECT Air patrols and firefighters will continue to monitor the 4,571 acre Wapiti Fire, located near Grandjean.The Wapiti Fire is 80 percent contained and 15 percent in monitor status.    The official handoff from the team to the local unit took place Monday September 3, at 6:30 a.m.   A few firefighters will continue to patrol containment lines to ensure they remain cold and black. A single torching of trees or smokes may be observed until significant moisture arrives in the area.Forest Service resource advisers have approved all restoration work.    Temperatures will generally remain the same and there is a chance of showers this weekend. Small amounts of smoke may be visible near the headwaters of Elk Creek and Bear Creek drainages until the area...</description></item><item><title>Red Feather Prescribed Burn (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 13:11:45 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 13:11:45 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>40.852222222222 -105.57555555556</georss:point><geo:lat>40.852222222222</geo:lat><geo:long>-105.57555555556</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5027/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5027/</guid><description>Update for September 13, 2018:Fire managers continue to monitor and patrol the perimeter of the Red Feather Prescribed burn north of Red Feather Lakes. Smoke and some interior flames will continue to be visible over the next few days as interior pockets of vegetation continue to burn. No active ignitions are planned. Currently the prescribed burn remains under 24 hour staffing. Earlier this week fire crews completed 958 acres of burning bringing the total accomplished to date since 2017 on the project to 4,150 acres. The purpose of the prescribed burn is to reduce elevated hazardous fuels near communities, promote more fire resilient landscapes and enhance wildlife habitat.Update for September 12, 2018:Fire managers continue to monitor and patrol the perimeter of the Red Feather Prescribed burn north of Red Feather Lakes. Smoke and some interior flames will continue to be visible over the next few days as interior pockets of vegetation continue to burn. No active ignitions are...</description></item><item><title>Crescent Mountain Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:57:05 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:57:05 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.451388888889 -120.57916666667</georss:point><geo:lat>48.451388888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-120.57916666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6093/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6093/</guid><description>   Evacuations:  As of 10:00 on September 8, 2018, all level 3 and 2 evacuations have been lifted. For further evacuation information, go to Okanogandem.org at: https://member.everbridge.net/index/453003085612200#/event The Crescent Mountain Fire started on July 29, 2018 in the headwaters of the Twisp River, approximately 21 miles from Twisp, Washington in the Okanogan - Wenatchee National Forest. The fire is currently being managed by the Northern Rockies National Incident Management Team #2.  Up-to-date area closure notices and evacuation levels are included in the daily updates, posted on this Inciweb page https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/news/6093/ , as well as on the incident Facebook page at https://www.facebook.com/CrescentMTNFire/.  </description></item><item><title>Iron East Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:43:58 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:43:58 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>47.3425 -120.68583333333</georss:point><geo:lat>47.3425</geo:lat><geo:long>-120.68583333333</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6195/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6195/</guid><description>At approximately 10pm on Friday, lightning started two fires in the Blewett Pass vicinity. Approximately 25 acres are burning to the east of Forest Road 9714 and 5-10 acres are burning to the west of Forest Road 9714. Level 2 evacuations are underway for homes 0.5 miles north of the fire. Three engines are positioned in the neighborhoods of the level 2 evacuations to maintain a presence on the ridge.The terrain is steep and forested. Crews cleared overgrown Forest Road 9714 up to the ridge in order to access the fires burning on each side. Hand crews are establishing a fire line around each fire, with dozers and engines assisting on the less steep eastern portion of the fire. Two engines, one from Ellensburg and one from Leavenworth, are attacking the eastern fire. The Washington Department of Transportation will close Highway 97 for one week to install culverts. Hikers and recreationalists in the vicinity of the fire have been cleared out by forest staff.On Saturday September 8th, at...</description></item><item><title>Donnell Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:16:45 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:16:45 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>38.348888888889 -119.92944444444</georss:point><geo:lat>38.348888888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-119.92944444444</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6092/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6092/</guid><description>  Donnell Fire Update  This will be the last Inciweb update  Wednesday, September 12, 2018 Stanislaus National Forest Type 3 IMT Steve Schulz, Incident Commander Matt Hilden, Incident Commander Donnell Fire Information: 209-432-3157 Donnell Fire Email: donnellfirestf1918@gmail.com Donnell Fire Website: https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6092/ Donnell Fire Facebook: www.facebook.com/StanislausNF   Fire Statistics: LOCATION: Stanislaus National Forest  DATE STARTED: August 1, 2018  ACRES: 36,450 acres  PERCENT CONTAINED: 90%  STRUCTURES THREATENED: 0  STRUCTURES DESTROYED: 54  INJURIES/ACCIDENTS: 9  MINOR STRUCTURES DESTROYED: 81  TOTAL PERSONNEL: 128  Fire Resources include: 5 Hand Crews, 2 Helicopters, 5 Engines, 4 Water Tenders  CURRENT SITUATION: The Pacific Crest Trail, Highland Lakes, Spicer Lake, and Forest Road 5N01 are open to public use. Clarification for 5N01; All spur roads heading North off the 5N01 will remain closed and all spur roads heading South off the 5N01 are open....</description></item><item><title>Bum Creek (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:10:50 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:10:50 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>44.994722222222 -115.30888888889</georss:point><geo:lat>44.994722222222</geo:lat><geo:long>-115.30888888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6197/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6197/</guid><description>The Bum Creek Fire was detected on September 7, 2018. It is a lightning caused fire burning in the Frank Church River of No Return Wilderness. The fire is under a monitor status, and is being allowed to play its natural role on the landscape, enhance and maintain wilderness character, and help restore ecological process in this forested ecosystem. Fire activity decreased yesterday, however the fire was active on Tuesday September 11. Tuesday's fire behavior increased the acres within the burned area to 1,820 acres. The fire pushed to east up Tamarack Creek where it ran into the burned area from the 2013 Thunder City Fire. Some spotting of the fire took place in the West Fork Monumental Creek Lakes area - those spots are mostly smoldering single logs. (Bum Creek Fire Map, September 13, 2018).Today's cooler temperatures, higher relative humidity and cloud cover, with a possibility of rain are expected to reduce fire behavior.The Communities of Yellowpine and Edwardsburg are not...</description></item><item><title>Beaver Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:10:02 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:10:02 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>45.893333333333 -113.5275</georss:point><geo:lat>45.893333333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-113.5275</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6147/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6147/</guid><description>  Beaver Creek fire: 2,074 acres, 35% contained, 8 personnel  Beaver Creek Fire: Smoke jumpers have secured the southern tip of the fire and have hiked out. A road grader is working to blade and smooth the road. All dozer lines have been rehabilitated, native seed has been ordered and will be planted on the dozer lines when it arrives. Crews have been cutting and removing tree and brush hazards along the roads. Cooler temperatures and shorter days have moderated and the fire behavior has reduced. No closures are in effect but public are reminded to stay out of the immediate fire area and away from any active burning and snags.   Additional Information: Fire Weather Forecast:  Showers today will bring fairly decent probabilities for a wetting rain to many locations, especially those districts across West Central (Bitterroot, Lolo NF) and SW Montana (Beaverhead/Deer Lodge). A dusting (less than 1 inch) of high mountain snow should be expected as well, generally above 7000 feet. Friday...</description></item><item><title>Goldstone Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:05:38 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:05:38 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>45.117222222222 -113.53444444444</georss:point><geo:lat>45.117222222222</geo:lat><geo:long>-113.53444444444</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6091/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6091/</guid><description>    Goldstone fire: 9,337 acres, (7,827 Beaverhead-Deerlodge NF, and 1,510 on the Salmon-Challis NF), 26% contained, 2 engines and 10 personnel    Goldstone Fire: Crews are continuing to take action on the fire where conditions are safe. Fuel breaks have been completed on the north and south flanks. Fire activity has reduced due to cooler temperatures and shorter days, however, smoke will continue to be visible in the Kenny Creek area and north of Reservoir Lake. This fire behavior will continue to be active until weather patterns change and significant season ending moisture arrives. Crews are currently working to conduct rehabilitation activities in key burned areas that will reduce erosion. They are also beginning to remove fallen and hazardous trees along the Continental Divide Trail where it traverses through the southern portion of the fire.   An objective on the Goldstone Fire is to implement strategies and tactics that minimize the risk and exposure to the firefighters. The...</description></item><item><title>Natchez Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:04:41 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:04:41 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>41.955833333333 -123.55138888889</georss:point><geo:lat>41.955833333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-123.55138888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5948/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5948/</guid><description> The Natchez Fire was started by lightning on July 15, 2018. The fire is located just south of the Oregon/California border between Happy Camp, CA and Cave Junction, OR.   NW Incident Management Team 7 (Eric Knerr-IC) assumed management of the Natchez Fire on September 4th and are working to implement suppression actions that will most effectively and safely limit fire growth.   Suppression operations include a mountain-to-mountain containment approach, using natural barriers and fire breaks through sparsely vegetated ridgetops, supplemented with retardant drops from aircraft. Where timber stringers represent a fuel bridge from one valley to the next, low-intensity ground- and aircraft-delivered ignitions have been used to improve control lines. This ridgeline containment strategy has worked to stop the fire spreading from Mud Lake to El Capitan.   Evacuations: Evacuation Warning notices are in place for three private in-holdings northwest of Happy Camp. Changes in these evacuation...</description></item><item><title>Mesa Fire (Burned Area Emergency Response)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:46:23 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:46:23 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>44.675833333333 -116.44777777778</georss:point><geo:lat>44.675833333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-116.44777777778</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6041/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6041/</guid><description>Firefighters have done an outstanding job of stopping the spread of the Mesa Fire east of Council. The Mesa Fire was human caused on July 26th, and burned 34,791 acres.The Mesa Fire Closure area has been reduced to only the southern portion of Cottonwood Creek Road (FS-199) being closed, efective Sept 12, 2018. The public can access the west side of Council Mountain via Mill Creek Road, to the open northern part of the Cottonwood Creek Road (FS-199), then to the Council Mountain Contour Road (FS-200) that leads to Cottonwood basin. Temporary gates will be placed at the closure points on Cottonwood Creek Road. The southern part of the Cottonwood Creek Road on National Forest Lands bore the brunt of the high intensity wildfire that burned through the area in late July. The road is closed to ensure public safety and to protect natural resources from further damage. The Cottonwood Creek Road is expected to remain closed through December 31, 2018, then depending on snow levels, it may be...</description></item><item><title>Caton Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:46:14 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:46:14 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>44.914166666667 -115.60416666667</georss:point><geo:lat>44.914166666667</geo:lat><geo:long>-115.60416666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6177/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6177/</guid><description> This fire was detected in heavy timber around noon on August 24 - a likely holdover from the lightning storm several days prior. The fire is located 7 miles southwest of Yellowpine, near Indian Point.Fire activity for the past several days has been minimal with very minor smokes on the west side of the fire, and one smoke on the southeast side of the fire down towards Caton Creek. Today's cooler temperatures and cloud cover, with a possibility of rain are expected toll further reduce fire behavior.Indian Peak Trail (FS #090) has an emergency closure on it - please do not use this trail. No Area Closures have been implemented at this time.  Firefighters are assigned to monitor the fire – additional fire resources will be assigned as needed. The fire is being managed under a confine/contain and point protection strategy.&amp;#183;Initial attack on this fire was rigorously conducted by smokejumpers, helirappellers, and ground crews aided by helicopters, single-engine air tankers, a heavy...</description></item><item><title>Rattlesnake Creek Fire (Burned Area Emergency Response)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:45:04 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:45:04 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>45.283611111111 -116.36694444444</georss:point><geo:lat>45.283611111111</geo:lat><geo:long>-116.36694444444</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5999/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5999/</guid><description>Cooler weather is expected to further minimize fire activity throughout this week. Some single tree, or group torching may take place in the east facing drainages on the Payette Nat'l part of the fire. The Portion of the fire on the Nez Perce - Clearwater National Forest has not seen fire activity for many days, and is not expected to occur.Firefighters and fire managers remain actively engaged on the fire with ground resources supported by aerial assets as needed to keep the fire in check. The Forest Service Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) Team is actively assessing fire impacts on federal lands within the fire area.Forest Service Trail #181 on the Payette National Forest is closed due to fire activity - please do not use this trail as it will interfere with our firefighting operations. Review the Payette National Forest Fire Closure at this link.Burned Area Emergency Recovery (BAER) efforts have begun on federal lands within the burned area. The Soils Burn Severity Map has...</description></item><item><title>Cougar Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:42:10 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:42:10 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>47.851388888889 -120.54916666667</georss:point><geo:lat>47.851388888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-120.54916666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6053/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6053/</guid><description>Randy Whitehall's Local Type 3 Incident Management Team assumed management of the Cougar Creek and Lost fires at 6 p.m. on Tuesday, September 11th. The two wildfires are burning on the Okanogan-Wenatchee National Forest land, Washington Department of Natural Resources land and private lands. Cougar Creek Fire: With more than 40,000 acres burned, is the largest of two wildfires. The fire is located approximately 10 miles northwest of Entiat, WA and 5 miles east of Plain, WA.  Lost Fire: The Lost Fire is being monitored by air. This 80-acre fire, located 10 miles north of Plain, WA, is fully contained.   U.S. Forest Service Closure Orders:    Cougar Creek and Lost Fires: https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/article/6053/47714/ </description></item><item><title>Hirz Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:39:52 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:39:52 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>40.890555555556 -122.22777777778</georss:point><geo:lat>40.890555555556</geo:lat><geo:long>-122.22777777778</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6116/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6116/</guid><description>  September 13, 2018 morning: Update | Map | 9/12 Evening Update Video | Smoke OutlookNew Announcement: Interstate 5 Open with Limited Traffic Control and Selected Shasta County Evacuations LiftedCurrent Situation: 46,150 Acres100% Contained185 PersonnelThe Hirz Fire is 100 percent contained. Firefighters will continue to patrol the fire permitter to ensure the fire stays within containment lines. Additional crews will continue suppression repair efforts in affected areas. Area, road, and trail closures remain in effect due to contained suppression repair work and additional hazards like snags. This incident will no longer be updated unless significant events require it.       Recreation Area Closures: view September 13, 2018 update  </description></item><item><title>2018 Umatilla NF Prescribed Fire (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:33:35 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:33:35 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>45.67 -118.87</georss:point><geo:lat>45.67</geo:lat><geo:long>-118.87</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5808/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5808/</guid><description>The Umatilla National Forest prescribed fire page contains public information on planned, active and completed prescribed burning for 2018 on the Forest. Burning is planned on each of the four Districts on the Umatilla National Forest. In general, there are two burn seasons each year to accomplish prescribed fire projects. Early season burns typically occur in late winter through the early fire season in late spring/early summer. Late season burns typically occur in late fire season and into December. The specific dates of a burn during a season is dependent on many variables including wildfire activity, resource availability, current and predicted weather, and smoke management constraints.  Frequent, low-intensity fire is essential for healthy forests and reducing the risk of uncharacteristic wildfire caused by excessive fuel buildup. Prescribed burning is an effective tool for removing excessive amounts of brush, shrubs, and trees, while also encouraging the growth of native...</description></item><item><title>McLeod Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:22:51 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:22:51 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.7075 -120.37222222222</georss:point><geo:lat>48.7075</geo:lat><geo:long>-120.37222222222</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6130/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6130/</guid><description>The McLeod Fire was first reported on August 11, 2018 during a dry lightning storm that started 20 new fires across the Okanogan-Wenatchee National Forest. Within 24 hours of initial attack on the new fire starts the majority of the fires were fully mopped up and in patrol status. The command of what would ultimately become two fires became the responsibility of the incident management team in place. The McLeod Fire was initially four fires (Panther, Isabella, Sunrise West, and McLeod) that have now merged to be known as the McLeod Fire. The fire is currently being managed along with the Crescent Mountain Fire.  Updates, maps, and closures for the Mcleod Fire will be posted here each morning.  For more photos of the fires, daily operational videos, and additional information, please visit the Crescent Mountain Inciweb page at https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6093/</description></item><item><title>Holman Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 09:56:46 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 09:56:46 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.830277777778 -120.74666666667</georss:point><geo:lat>48.830277777778</geo:lat><geo:long>-120.74666666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6164/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6164/</guid><description>The Holman Fire, burning approximately 100 acres in a wilderness area, is posing no threat to infrastructure or private homes. Though unstaffed at this time, the Southern Area Blue Team is managing and monitoring this fire.This page will not be updated unless significant changes occur on the fire.</description></item><item><title>Rabbit Foot Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 08:50:29 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 08:50:29 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>44.856388888889 -114.30666666667</georss:point><geo:lat>44.856388888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-114.30666666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6090/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6090/</guid><description> The lightning-caused Rabbit Foot Fire began on August 2, 2018, and is burning in steep terrain, primarily in timber and standing dead tree snags. Initially, the fire spread quickly through dense timber but has since moderated due to more favorable weather conditions. The fire is being managed by a local Type III Incident Management Team.   Area and road closures on National Forest System lands are in effect and are being evaluated by fire managers and local agency officials for the potential to reopen when the safety of firefighters and the public can be reasonably assured.   Level 1 pre-evacuation notices have been issued for some residents along the Hwy 93 corridor in Custer and Lemhi counties. Residents are encouraged to sign up for emergency notifications through their county’s CodeRed reverse 9-1-1 service.  Strategy: The Rabbit Foot Fire is being managed using a combination of actions, some directly adjacent to the fire perimeter and others long distances away from the active...</description></item><item><title>Kiwah Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 08:49:38 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 08:49:38 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>44.822777777778 -115.28638888889</georss:point><geo:lat>44.822777777778</geo:lat><geo:long>-115.28638888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5995/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5995/</guid><description>The lightning caused Kiwah Fire, was detected at approximately 5:30 p.m. on July 17, 2018. Fire managers estimate size at 14,603 acres. The fire is burning in a mixed conifer forest on the Middle Fork Ranger District and is being allowed to play, as nearly as possible, its natural ecological role in the environment while providing for firefighter and public safety. The fire is located in steep, inaccessible terrain northwest of Indian Creek Guard Station within the Indian Creek drainage in the Frank Church River of No Return Wilderness. Fire activity remains minimal throughout the fire area. Fire managers expect the Kiwah Fire will continue to burn until a significant precipitation event occurs. Typically, season-ending weather events occur in this area between the last half of September through the first half of October.  The Central Idaho Dispatch Zone is at HIGH Fire Danger. Nationally, there are 24 uncontained large fires in the west managed under a full suppression strategy, and...</description></item><item><title>2018 Malheur NF Prescribed Fire (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 19:54:05 -05:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 19:54:05 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>44.417777777778 -118.95138888889</georss:point><geo:lat>44.417777777778</geo:lat><geo:long>-118.95138888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5139/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5139/</guid><description>   This prescribed fire incident has been established to provide public information on planned, active and completed prescribed burning for 2018 on the Malheur National Forest. Burning is planned on each of the three Districts on the Malheur NF:        Blue Mountain District, office in John Day, OR     Prairie City District, office in Prairie City, OR     Emigrant Creek District, office in Hines, OR       Prescribed fires, also known as controlled burns, refer to the planned and controlled use of fire by a team of experts under specific conditions of temperature, wind, and humidity. Prescribed fire is used to help restore ecosystems that depend on fire, reduce the risk of out-of-control wildfire, and increase community and firefighter safety.NEW! Prescribed Fire Activity Interactive Map Link (This interactive map is best viewed using Chrome, Safari, Firefox or Internet Explorer 9 or higher).    The data represents the recently completed, active, upcoming, and out-year prescribed fire...</description></item><item><title>Ranch Fire BAER (Burned Area Emergency Response)</title><published>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:45:05 -05:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:45:05 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>39.234722222222 -122.76583333333</georss:point><geo:lat>39.234722222222</geo:lat><geo:long>-122.76583333333</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6156/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6156/</guid><description>The Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) team is getting established in Upper Lake to start working on its assessment and recommendations to lessen immediate hazards to public resources from effects of the Ranch Fire. The purpose of the BAER assessment is to analyze fire effects on soils and watersheds, determine the potential for negative effects, and consider possible treatment options. The threat to life and property is always the number one concern and is the first focus of the burned area assessment.</description></item><item><title>Cache Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:39:37 -05:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:39:37 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>39.403611111111 -107.88972222222</georss:point><geo:lat>39.403611111111</geo:lat><geo:long>-107.88972222222</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6052/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6052/</guid><description>#CacheCreekFire Update Sept. 12, 2018:Due to warm, dry and breezy weather there is some smoldering and creeping fire activity within the perimeter of the Cache Creek Fire. Smoke is visible from the I-70 corridor and is coming from within the fire perimeter and containment line, primarily the southern portion of the fire. Please do not call 911. Firefighters and fire managers are aware of the activity and are monitoring. No structures, private property or infrastructure are threatened at this time. Firefighters went out to the fire today to assess the activity. Tomorrow, additional resources will be patrolling the fire.For continued information please call the Rifle Ranger District at</description></item><item><title>Coal Hollow Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:07:05 -05:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:07:05 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>39.950833333333 -111.4025</georss:point><geo:lat>39.950833333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-111.4025</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6101/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6101/</guid><description>The Coal Hollow fire transitioned to a Type 3 local team Thursday, Aug. 30, 6 a.m. Fire behavior is minimal with creeping and smoldering within the interior of the fire. Fire is currently at 29,912 acres and 80% contained. Closure orders remain in place with evacuations ordered immediately near the fire perimeter and where firefighting activities are taking place. Any uncontained line has the potential to heat and actively start burning. Final rehab of suppression related impacts is being completed. Crews will continue suppression repair, grid for hot spots and mop-up to secure control lines. They will patrol and monitor areas of indirect line for active fire</description></item><item><title>North Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 16:03:01 -05:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 16:03:01 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>39.277777777778 -120.66305555556</georss:point><geo:lat>39.277777777778</geo:lat><geo:long>-120.66305555556</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6188/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6188/</guid><description>As of 6 a.m. today, September 12, management of the North Fire is under the Tahoe NF. The new Fire Information Phone Number is 530-478-6880. Phone lines will be staffed from 8 am - 5 pm daily. Suppression repair work continues today, along with patrol and mop up. The North Fire is at 97%</description></item><item><title>Stewart Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 10:36:14 -05:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 10:36:14 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>43.49 -115.05722222222</georss:point><geo:lat>43.49</geo:lat><geo:long>-115.05722222222</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6171/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6171/</guid><description>The Stewart Creek Fire started on August 20, 2018 resulting from dry lightning, 18 miles Northwest of Fairfield, Idaho on the Sawtooth National Forest, Fairfield Ranger District. Weather conditions, dry fuels and rough terrain aided in fire spread, showing signs of up to ½ mile of spotting potential. Crews strategically stationed at various spike camps have been working tirelessly on this fire to build fireline where accessible to help impede fire spread and guide the fire to the east and north. Available air resources are being used in inaccessible and dangerous areas where firefighters are unable to safely operate due to extremely steep terrain or hazardous standing dead trees, also known as ‘snags.’ The fire is burning in standing timber, heavy down and dead understory with visible single tree and group torching. The Eastern Area Incident Management Team took command of the fire on August 31st. After nearly two weeks of managing the fire and reaching 60% containment, the fire...</description></item><item><title>Perkins Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 09:22:43 -05:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 09:22:43 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>35.1025 -112.04722222222</georss:point><geo:lat>35.1025</geo:lat><geo:long>-112.04722222222</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6180/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6180/</guid><description> A new lightning caused wildfire that was discovered on August 25 on the Williams Ranger District will be allowed to move naturally to benefit the landscape. The 121 acre Perkins Fire is located approximately 2 miles southwest of White Horse Lake and is burning slowly in grass, ponderosa pine and oak litter near the junction of forest roads 109 and 110.  This fire will be visible to visitors, campers and hunters who frequently travel the 109 and 110 corridors into adjacent recreational areas. Managers ask that all who travel through the vicinity be aware of fire apparatus and personnel working along roadways. They also recommend campers avoid establishing campsites close to the area where active fire is occurring or is anticipated to move. </description></item><item><title>Brownstone Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 16:38:24 -05:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 16:38:24 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>47.518888888889 -113.18833333333</georss:point><geo:lat>47.518888888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-113.18833333333</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6103/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6103/</guid><description>The Brownstone Fire was detected on August 2nd, 2018. The fire is burning in the Bob Marshall Wilderness and was ignited by lightning on July 28th. As a result of significant fire activity in the mouth of the Brownstone Creek drainage on September 8th, the decision was made to begin firing operations during favorable conditions on September 9th in order to secure the south end of the historic Big Prairie Ranger Station compound. Fire personnel constructed a fire line using a trail plow drug by a mule – you can find an example of trail plow use here: https://www.facebook.com/discovertheflathead/videos/967829346660030/. The line is anchored at the creek that held the 2011 Hammer Creek Fire and runs along the south end of the jack leg fence at compound. Firefighters took advantage of the favorable conditions and implemented the burnout as planned. The firing operation continued into the evening hours of September 9th, and successfully completed securing the south end of the compound....</description></item><item><title>Stadler Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 15:44:46 -05:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 15:44:46 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>47.444166666667 -113.0325</georss:point><geo:lat>47.444166666667</geo:lat><geo:long>-113.0325</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6194/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6194/</guid><description>The Stadler Fire was detected on September 7th, 2018, and is burning in the Stadler Creek drainage within the Bob Marshall Wilderness.The fire is burning 4 miles to the east of Basin Cabin, and is currently not a threat. Minimal activity was observed from date of detection through September 10th. The situation will be monitored carefully; structure protection equipment and personnel are on standby.  Trail closures have been implemented as of September 8th; closure maps have been posted. On the Spotted Bear Ranger District, the Stadler Creek Trail #271 is closed in its entirety from the junction with Danaher Creek Trail #126 to its terminus at Stadler Pass. On the Rocky Mountain Ranger District, the Hoadley Creek Trail #266 is closed from Stadler Pass/Continental Divide and continues northeast to the junction with the East Fork Ahorn Creek Trail #225.</description></item><item><title>Juliet Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 15:25:05 -05:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 15:25:05 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>47.747222222222 -113.19916666667</georss:point><geo:lat>47.747222222222</geo:lat><geo:long>-113.19916666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6168/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6168/</guid><description> The Juliet Fire was detected on August 22nd, 2018 and is burning in the upper White River within the Bob Marshall Wilderness.  The Juliet Fire was significantly less active on September 9th and 10th compared to the previous week. The fire burning in the upper end of the Wall Creek drainage has reached the 2012 Wall Creek Fire burn scar. The previous fire has significantly slowed current fire activity in this area. The fire is creeping in Hoop Creek; intermittent single tree torching was observed. The previous spot fire that had established in the headwaters of Juliet Creek continues to slowly creep towards the Continental Divide near My Lake. Meanwhile, the fire continues to burn further up Larch Hill on the southern flank, and up Pedro Creek to the northwest of the Wall Creek Cliffs. The fire activity in Pedro Creek remains fairly active.  Trail closures remain in place, including the Continental Divide National Scenic Trail (CDT). The Moose Fire to the east of the divide has also...</description></item><item><title>Cabin Lake Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 12:24:49 -05:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 12:24:49 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>39.916388888889 -107.63972222222</georss:point><geo:lat>39.916388888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-107.63972222222</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6057/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6057/</guid><description>Cabin Lake Fire InformationSEPT. 11, 2018CABIN LAKE FIRE 98% CONTAINED; FOREST CLOSURES REDUCEDBUFORD, CO – The Cabin Lake Fire has been burning for 45 days; today, it is 98% contained, and management of the fire will transition from a Type 3 to a local Type 4 organization. County Road 17/ the Buford-Newcastle Road is open, and Forest Service lands on the west side of the road have re-opened. East of County Road 17, the forest closure will remain in effect from the roadside to the South Fork drainage and to the base of Burro Mountain. The burned area within the fire perimeter will remain closed until containment is complete.Large sections of the fire perimeter have been mopped up and cooled several hundred feet in from the fire containment line. Fuels remain available within the fire perimeter, and isolated smokes may continue to be visible. Infrared flights have been flown daily; they continue to detect hot spots in the interior. Crews will cool these areas of heat and continue mop...</description></item><item><title>Blue Ridge Prescribed Burn (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 12:12:31 -05:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 12:12:31 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>40.041388888889 -106.08916666667</georss:point><geo:lat>40.041388888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-106.08916666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6198/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6198/</guid><description> The U.S. Forest Service’s Arapaho National Forest is preparing to apply prescribed fire in the area known as “Blue Ridge” south of Hot Sulphur Springs and southwest of Granby, Colo. Implementing prescribed fire is the next step in the Blue Ridge Salvage and Fuels Reduction Project, an on-going effort to reduce the risk of wildfire to communities and improve forest health conditions in Grand County. Burning could take place in the fall and spring, and fire managers hope to start with a few small units (about 500 acres total) later this fall in the northernmost portion of the project area, between Big Meadows and Cottonwood Pass.  The area is part of the Wildland-Urban Interface formed by the towns of Granby, Hot Sulphur Springs and the Fraser Valley. Improving conditions in this area is a key component of the Hot Sulphur, Fraser and Grand County Community Wildfire Protection Plans.</description></item><item><title>South Sugarloaf Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 20:11:07 -05:00</published><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 20:11:07 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>41.811666666667 -116.32388888889</georss:point><geo:lat>41.811666666667</geo:lat><geo:long>-116.32388888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6166/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6166/</guid><description>﻿With the South Sugarloaf Fire reaching 98 percent containment, the Humboldt-Toiyabe National Forest is again reducing the fire area closure on the Mountain City-Ruby Mountains-Jarbidge Ranger District. The change takes effect Thursday, Sept. 6. All of hunting units 061 and 071 will now be open. Portions of 062 remain closed. Big Bend campground has opened for public use. Fire operations traffic still exist along the roadways and motorists are asked to continue using safe driving practices.A press release and new closure map is posted on</description></item><item><title>Sugarloaf Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 16:56:17 -05:00</published><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 16:56:17 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>39.811944444444 -105.99527777778</georss:point><geo:lat>39.811944444444</geo:lat><geo:long>-105.99527777778</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5872/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5872/</guid><description> Sugarloaf Fire Update Facebook: @usfsarp or https://www.facebook.com/usfsarp/ Twitter: @usfsarp or https://twitter.com/usfsarp #SugarloafFire History: The Sugarloaf Fire started on Thursday, June 28, 2018, from a lightning strike near the South Fork of Darling Creek, just south of Byers Peak Wilderness. The area is rugged and steep, remote with no roads and no safety zones for firefighters. It is part of a mountain pine beetle epidemic that devastated lodgepole pine forests 20 years ago in various parts of the Forest. The numerous dead trees still standing now present a particularly dangerous condition from extreme overhead hazards and high potential for sudden and unexpected tree fall.  Management: Type 4 Incident Management Team. The Sugarloaf Fire is being managed under a suppression strategy. The number one goal is to protect the public and firefighters, followed by protection of private and public property and infrastructure. Size: 1,280 acres Contained: 35% Resources Assigned:...</description></item><item><title>Stina Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 13:50:02 -05:00</published><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 13:50:02 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>36.370555555556 -112.34166666667</georss:point><geo:lat>36.370555555556</geo:lat><geo:long>-112.34166666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6107/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6107/</guid><description>Firefighters and fire managers continue working to contain the Stina Fire, burning since July 26, 2018. As fire suppression activities wind down, crews have begun the task of cleaning up after all their hard work. The task of mitigating the impact of the fight to stop the fire is referred to as “suppression</description></item><item><title>Taylor Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 13:03:44 -05:00</published><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 13:03:44 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>42.528055555556 -123.57138888889</georss:point><geo:lat>42.528055555556</geo:lat><geo:long>-123.57138888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6058/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6058/</guid><description>The Taylor Creek and Klondike Fires are burning in the Rogue River-Siskiyou National Forest. Both fires were started by lightning on July 15. The Taylor Creek Fire is being managed by a Type 3 Incident Management Team led by Derrick Davenport out of the Forest Service’s Wild Rivers Ranger Station in Cave Junction, and along with the East Zone of the Klondike Fire. Taylor Creek Fire is estimated 52,839 acres and is currently 95 percent contained. Work has begun to repair contingency and alternate lines that were constructed during the suppression phase. Repair activities include repairing culverts, grading heavily used roads, removing dozer burms and constructing waterbars on steep slopes. The recovery of timber that was damaged during suppression efforts is also ongoing. No additional fire growth is expected on the Taylor Creek or the East Zone of the Klondike Fire as there are well tested fire-lines or recent burn scars surrounding the perimeter. Residents of the Illinois River...</description></item><item><title>Valley Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 12:39:42 -05:00</published><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 12:39:42 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>34.095555555556 -116.95777777778</georss:point><geo:lat>34.095555555556</geo:lat><geo:long>-116.95777777778</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5900/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5900/</guid><description>The fire remains in in steep, inaccessible terrain and has shown no new smoke or flame in recent weeks after a number of episdoes of hot and dry weather. The fire is in patrol status and may only declared fully contained after the first significant precipitation event of the fall or winter. Due to the extended period of time until full containment, this InciWeb page will not be updated daily. The Valley Fire Closure Area was lifted on Thursday, August 30, 2018. That means all areas of San Gorgonio Wilderness previously closed due to the fire are now open. For permits, go to the Mill Creek Ranger Station. </description></item><item><title>Lake Christine Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 12:32:32 -05:00</published><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 12:32:32 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>39.371111111111 -107.04277777778</georss:point><geo:lat>39.371111111111</geo:lat><geo:long>-107.04277777778</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5895/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5895/</guid><description>Lake Christine Fire update for the week of September 10, 2018: The Lake Christine Fire remains at 90% containment with no new growth in the past several weeks. Minimal fire behavior still persists within the interior of the fire with some smoldering and interior smokes where pockets of heat still exist. Firefighters continue to conduct mop-up and patrol containment lines. This past weekend, six firefighters flew into an interior portion of the fire that was deemed safe to work in to conduct mop-up on a smoldering hot spot. Additionally, over the weekend, water bucket drops were applied to all interior smokes/hot spots. Periodic smokes are expected to persist this week with warm, dry weather. Sixteen firefighters remain on the Lake Christine Fire conducting suppression repair and mop-up operations. Thank you for your continued patience and adherence to the area closure while suppression operations are ongoing. For continued updates please visit https://www.fs.usda.gov/whiteriver or...</description></item><item><title>Lions Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 11:48:18 -05:00</published><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 11:48:18 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>37.571111111111 -119.11833333333</georss:point><geo:lat>37.571111111111</geo:lat><geo:long>-119.11833333333</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5850/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5850/</guid><description>This will be the final update for the Lions Fire as an active incident. The fire will be placed in a monitoring status. Containment numbers will be updated as final heat pockets dissipate and season ending weather arrives.Fire crews worked successfully and held containment lines as the fire met rock face in other areas, slowly consuming the remaining fuel. The infrared (IR) and reconnaissance flights this weekend showed minimal fire growth. Aircraft continued to provide personnel and equipment retrieval until all personnel were off of the incident. Suppression repair has been underway and finished on Sunday, with those crews being released and made available for other fire assignments. Due to the near vertical terrain on parts of the north and west flanks, containment will remain at 85% until a season ending weather event occurs, or IR flights show no trace of heat. It is too dangerous to place fire fighters into those areas to check the ground by hand. The Sierra National Forest will...</description></item><item><title>Watson Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:55:51 -05:00</published><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 22:55:51 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>42.649722222222 -120.8275</georss:point><geo:lat>42.649722222222</geo:lat><geo:long>-120.8275</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6153/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6153/</guid><description>The Watson Creek Fire is burning on the Paisley Ranger District of the Fremont-Winema National Forest. It was discovered Wednesday, August 15th at 2:15 p.m. approximately 13 miles west of Paisley, Oregon. The fire is burning in a combination of timber, brush and logging slash of mixed conifers and contains significant dead</description></item><item><title>Britania Mountain Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 09:10:32 -05:00</published><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 09:10:32 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>42.115 -105.36638888889</georss:point><geo:lat>42.115</geo:lat><geo:long>-105.36638888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6179/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6179/</guid><description>The Britania Mountain Fire is currently 32,089 acres and the fire is 95% contained. On Thursday, containment gains were made in Division Z on the southwest corner of the fire. Crews working along Palmer Canyon Road began chipping green vegetation that was cut to construct control lines. Chipping operations started on the east end of the road in Platte County and have progressed west into Albany County. Firefighters mopped up and extinguished hot spots on Division W adding more depth to control lines. On cold sections of the fire, crews removed hose, portable water tanks, and other firefighting equipment to be returned to supply caches for refurbishing. Divisions A and M were put into patrol status and monitored by engine crews. Today, mop up efforts will be focused on the western side of the fire in Division W. Chipping operations will extend west along Palmer Canyon Road. While chipping operations are occurring the road will remain closed for firefighter and public safety. Area...</description></item><item><title>Rattlesnake Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 08:50:51 -05:00</published><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 08:50:51 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>47.753333333333 -114.52888888889</georss:point><geo:lat>47.753333333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-114.52888888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6182/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6182/</guid><description> The Rattlesnake Fire is a human-caused incident, located 10 miles northeast of the town of Hot Springs, on the Flathead Indian Reservation in Lake County. It is burning in grass and timber along a steep west facing slope. The fire is being managed by a local Type 3 Incident Management Team. There are 160 personnel assigned to the incident. The fire is 1,374 acres and 69% contained. For details on past and planned fire management activity please see the attached articles, including the one dated for today, Sept. 6.</description></item><item><title>Rampike Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 14:57:18 -05:00</published><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 14:57:18 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>47.848611111111 -115.96666666667</georss:point><geo:lat>47.848611111111</geo:lat><geo:long>-115.96666666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6126/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6126/</guid><description>INFORMATION ON THE RAMPIKE FIRE WILL BE UPDATED WEEKLY EACH FRIDAYThe Rampike Fire was detected on 7/31/2018 and caused by lightning the previous weekend. Burning 1.5 miles east of Shoshone Creek, the fire is on a ridge between Clinton Creek and Rampike Creek. With firefighter and public safety being the number one priority, area closures are in place on the Idaho Panhandle and Kootenai National Forests. Please see the Closures and Maps tabs for further information. Stage I fire restrictions are in effect on the Idaho Panhandle National Forests and Stage II fire restrictions are in effect on the Kootenai National Forest. Know before you go and contact your local Ranger District for details.</description></item><item><title>Gance Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 13:45:45 -05:00</published><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 13:45:45 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>41.303333333333 -115.97416666667</georss:point><geo:lat>41.303333333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-115.97416666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6186/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6186/</guid><description>  The Gance Fire is holding at 5,363 acres and is now 75% contained. The Nevada Type 3 Team 4 Britt is transitioning the wildfire back to the Mountain City-Ruby Mountains-Jarbidge Ranger District on Saturday and Forest staff will continue to patrol and monitor the fire.  Smoldering vegetation may remain within the fire perimeter. The cause of the fire is under investigation.  Approximately 179 personnel remain working on the fire from agencies including Bureau of Indian Affairs, Bureau of Land Management, Elko County, Forest Service, and Nevada Division of Forestry. Resources on the fire include: five hand crews, 23 engines, two helicopters, two bulldozers, two water tenders, and one Very Large Air Tanker (VLAT).  </description></item><item><title>Bull Draw Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 12:27:27 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 12:27:27 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>38.456944444444 -108.665</georss:point><geo:lat>38.456944444444</geo:lat><geo:long>-108.665</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6059/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6059/</guid><description>September 5, 2018This will be the final update for Bull Draw Fire, pending any further developments.Current Situation: The Bull Draw Fire has transitioned to a Type 4 organization. Please continue to follow the Bull Draw Facebook page (www.facebook.com/BullDrawFire) or call GMUG Fire Information Line at (970) 874-6602The fire remains at 30,580 acres and is 60% contained. Fire activity was low again yesterday due to precipitation, higher humidity levels, cloud cover and lower temperatures. On the fire; work in Division “W” has been completed and it moved into patrol status. On the northside, staff will continue to monitor fire spread and potential near Long Canyon and the north and northeastern fire perimeter.On Wednesday, September 4, The Grand Mesa, Uncompahgre and Gunnison (GMUG) National Forests reduced the closure area around the Bull Draw Fire. Public access to the following areas of the Uncompahgre National Forest’s Plateau Division will be limited:The area is bordered on...</description></item><item><title>Coal Hollow BAER (Burned Area Emergency Response)</title><published>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 10:09:05 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 10:09:05 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>39.950833333333 -111.4025</georss:point><geo:lat>39.950833333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-111.4025</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6184/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6184/</guid><description>Coal Hollow Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) team assembled Aug. 29 and began its assessment of the Coal Hollow Fire burn scar. It is under the direction of Mike Natharius, a soil scientist. The team will perform a burned area survey to determine if emergency treatments are warranted. They are looking at natural and cultural resource damage and potential for damage from the first damaging post-fire rain event. BAER team surveys are rapid assessments of the burned area that evaluate the burned watersheds and determine the potential for increased post-fire flooding, sediment flows, and rock slides that may have unacceptable risk to life, property, natural or cultural resources.The Forest Service program is aimed at managing imminent unacceptable risks to human life and safety, property, or critical natural and cultural resources due to potential damaging events generated or exacerbated by wildfire. They will also assess the potential for spread of noxious weeds and public safety...</description></item><item><title>Owl Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 23:43:11 -05:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 23:43:11 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>40.656666666667 -115.51833333333</georss:point><geo:lat>40.656666666667</geo:lat><geo:long>-115.51833333333</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6183/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6183/</guid><description>The #OwlCreekFire located near Spring Creek, Nevada, and started at 7:45 p.m. on Thursday, Aug.30 on private land and moved onto the Mountain City-Ruby Mountains-Jarbidge Ranger District of the Humboldt-Toiyabe National Forest. It is south of Lamoilla Canyon. Fire officials ask the public to please stay out the vicinity of the Pleasant Valley Road near the Spring Creek Association campground and shooting range complex due to fire operations. These facilities are closed until further notice. There are no Forest Service closures at this time and the fire is under investigation.For additional fire information, please call Owl Creek Fire Public Officer staff at 775-771-4777 or get the latest fire updates on Twitter @HumboldtToiyabe or Facebook @HumboldtToiyabeNF (Use hashtag</description></item><item><title>Rocky Mountain Region-2018 PostFire BAER (Burned Area Emergency Response)</title><published>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 19:15:41 -05:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 19:15:41 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>39.371111111111 -107.04305555556</georss:point><geo:lat>39.371111111111</geo:lat><geo:long>-107.04305555556</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5928/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5928/</guid><description>   Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) teams have been established to begin burned area surveys of the wildfires that recently burned on federal lands of the U.S. Forest Service – Rocky Mountain Region. BAER team surveys are rapid assessments of the burned areas that evaluate post-fire conditions of the burned watersheds and determine the potential for increased post-fire flooding, sediment flows, and rock slides.      BAER teams consist of scientists and specialists including hydrologists, geologists, soil scientists, road engineers, botanists, wildlife and fisheries biologists, archeologists, recreation and trails specialists, and geographic information specialists, from federal and state agencies. BAER teams work together during the burned area surveys, field data analysis and modeling phase, to present findings along with recommended BAER treatments to the Forest Supervisor.      BAER teams analyze the data they collect during the surveys, to produce a “Soil Burn Severity”...</description></item><item><title>Ferguson Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 11:41:52 -05:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 11:41:52 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>37.651944444444 -119.88111111111</georss:point><geo:lat>37.651944444444</geo:lat><geo:long>-119.88111111111</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5927/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5927/</guid><description> SUMMARY  The Ferguson Fire started on Friday night, July 13 at 9:36 PM in the South Fork Merced River drainage on Sierra National Forest. In the steep, rugged terrain, with scarcely any road access and a heavy presence of beetle-killed trees, firefighters knew it would be more than a challenge to contain.  In the first 24 hours, it had grown to 828 acres, as management of the fire was taken over by the Southern Central Sierra Interagency Management Team Type 2 and an incident command post was set up at Ahawahnee Hills Regional Park near Oakhurst, California. Under unified command between the U.S. Forest Service, Cal Fire, and the Mariposa County Sheriff, the community of Jerseydale among others were evacuated. Also on the second day of the fire, heavy equipment operator Braden Varney from the Cal Fire Madera-Mariposa-Merced unit was tragically killed in a bulldozer rollover accident while constructing line in a steep canyon.   One week later, management of the fire transitioned on...</description></item><item><title>Stone Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 11:18:10 -05:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 11:18:10 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>41.395 -121.05722222222</georss:point><geo:lat>41.395</geo:lat><geo:long>-121.05722222222</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6148/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6148/</guid><description>    THIS WILL BE THE LAST UPDATE FOR THE STONE FIRE from NorCal Team 2.  Additional updates will be posted only if conditions change, and can be found at  inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6148 or on Facebook @ModocNF.  NorCal Team 2 will transfer command of the Stone Fire to a Type 3 Modoc National Forest organization at 6:00 a.m. on Thursday, August 30, 2018.  The Stone Fire remains at 39,387 acres and is 100% contained.  Mop up and patrol will continue today. Crews are anticipating a shift back into warmer, breezier conditions, and they will look carefully for any hot spots or snags that begin to show activity. Green islands of vegetation within the fire perimeter are continuing to ignite and burn, and residents and motorists should expect to see smoke within the fire perimeter for the next few days. The fire will be staffed into the foreseeable future to ensure that lines remain secure.  For more information and a photo gallery of the fire, please visit...</description></item><item><title>Horns Mountain (Wildfire)</title><published>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 13:43:49 -05:00</published><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 13:43:49 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.98 -118.05083333333</georss:point><geo:lat>48.98</geo:lat><geo:long>-118.05083333333</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6138/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6138/</guid><description>Horns Mountain Fire is mostly in patrol status. Type 3 team will transition to Colville National Forest for management of the fire on Tuesday 4</description></item><item><title>Boyds Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 12:45:17 -05:00</published><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 12:45:17 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.602222222222 -118.14055555556</georss:point><geo:lat>48.602222222222</geo:lat><geo:long>-118.14055555556</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6139/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6139/</guid><description>Firefighters are continuing to mop-up and check for hot spots. All evacuations on the Boyd’s fire have been lifted.NE IMT Team #1 has taken command of the fire on Wednesday, August 29, 2018 at 6:00 am. Numerous fires are burning within the region contributing to smoke in the area. The Northeast Tri County Health District has information concerning air quality for this area. Please contact the health district at: https://www.netchd.org/for further information or visit:</description></item><item><title>Redinger Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 17:14:09 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 17:14:09 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>37.168611111111 -119.41916666667</georss:point><geo:lat>37.168611111111</geo:lat><geo:long>-119.41916666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6178/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6178/</guid><description> The Redinger Fire which started approximately ¼ of a mile above the Redinger Overlook on Forest Road 81, is 100% contained. After a reconnaissance flight for more accurate mapping occurred, the fire consumed 88 acres. Today, fire crews have begun suppression repair of the perimeter where handline, dozer line, and natural features were used as a containment break, removing hoselines and equipment used in their fire suppression operations. Crews will also continue to patrol the fire, mop-up hotspots, and remove hazard vegetation along the perimeter into the burn area as needed.     The Castle Fire which started about ½ mile above the Redinger Fire has burned 7.5 acres, a drop in acres due to more accurate mapping and is also 100% contained. Crews are focused now with mop-up, and suppression repair activities. There are still hotspots and smoldering from within the interior of the burn area.  Fire crews and apparatus will still be present on Forest Road 81, in the coming days and over...</description></item><item><title>Maple Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 10:45:31 -05:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 10:45:31 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>47.5775 -123.13</georss:point><geo:lat>47.5775</geo:lat><geo:long>-123.13</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6111/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6111/</guid><description> The Maple Fire remains within the identified containment lines and firefighters are monitoring growth along Jefferson Ridge as the wildfire continues to slowly creep to the west. The fire has not moved to the northeast or south but is expected to continue to spread west due to steep, inaccessible terrain. Crews will focus on holding and improving roads, rivers and creeks where the fire is currently held in check. The fire is expected to continue burning and emitting smoke until steady, seasonal rains extinguish it.  Smoky conditions may continue to affect communities in the region. For information about how to deal with smoky conditions, go to: wasmoke.blogsport.com or airnow.gov. For information on air quality, go to: Regional Clean Air Agencies  The local Olympic Interagency Fire Management team will continue to work to meet objectives identified by the Olympic National Forest (ONF) and the Washington Department of Natural Resources (DNR). The ever-present threat of both live and...</description></item><item><title>Tonto National Forest Rx Burns 2018 (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 17:09:31 -05:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 17:09:31 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>34.354722222222 -111.09416666667</georss:point><geo:lat>34.354722222222</geo:lat><geo:long>-111.09416666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5925/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5925/</guid><description>Prescribed fires are essential tools for restoring the forest in our fire adapted ecosystem, and smoke is an unavoidable byproduct of these vital efforts. Fire managers strive to minimize smoke impacts to the community as much as possible. They burn when winds and other atmospheric conditions will push the majority of smoke away from homes; they will burn larger sections at a time to limit the number of days smoke is in the air, and they work closely with the Arizona Department of Environmental Quality, as well as neighboring forests to monitor air quality.Crews also seek opportunities to use slash from thinning projects around the community instead of burning it. It is often used s filler at the landfill and offered as firewood to community members. Forests need the frequent, low intensity fire to remove accumulated smaller fuels and recycle nutrients into the soils to promote healthy vegetation and wildlife habitat. A healthier forest is a safer forest for firefighters and residents...</description></item><item><title>Front Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 12:28:13 -05:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 12:28:13 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>35.116666666667 -120.10055555556</georss:point><geo:lat>35.116666666667</geo:lat><geo:long>-120.10055555556</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6158/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6158/</guid><description> Aug 24, 0630: This will be the last update unless fire conditions change significantly. Firefighters are near full containment of the Front Fire, located at the Rockfront OHV area on the Santa Lucia Ranger District. Favorable weather has helped firefighters continue to strengthen containment lines. Steep uneven terrain and hazard trees are still a risk, so firefighter and public safety are top priorities. Complete fire containment is predicted by Aug 29. Some priority resources have been released to assist other fires, while ensuring continued coverage as needed on the Front Fire.  Forest Restriction: As a reminder, the following is restricted in all areas of the Los Padres National Forest with a few exceptions. Wood and charcoal fires, fireworks, Smoking, and recreational target shooting are prohibited. Hunting is not allowed in the fire closure areas. Operating or using any internal or external combustion engine without a spark arresting device properly installed, maintained and in...</description></item><item><title>Fleming Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 13:02:13 -05:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 13:02:13 -05:00</pubDate><georss:point>48.787777777778 -116.37638888889</georss:point><geo:lat>48.787777777778</geo:lat><geo:long>-116.37638888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6172/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6172/</guid><description>The Fleming Creek Fire is burning on industrial timberland and other private lands north of Fleming Creek Road and west of Lupine Road.  The fire is burning in timber and logging slash. Containment is at 100% and firefighters will continue to strengthen fireline and mop-up interior hotspots.     An Idaho interagency Type 3 Incident Management Team is managing the fire through Tuesday, August 28.    The fire was reported August 24 at approximately 12 P.M. The cause of the fire is under investigation. Current Fire UpdateFire Map </description></item></channel></rss>